Others played the game. He changed it.
Iverson is a documentary film directed by Zatella Beatty.
Iverson is the ultimate legacy of NBA legend Allen Iverson, who rose from a childhood of crushing poverty in
Hampton, Virginia, to become an 11-time NBA All-Star and universally recognized icon of his sport.
Off the court, his audacious rejection of conservative NBA convention and unapologetic embrace of hip
hop culture sent shockwaves throughout the league and influenced an entire generation.
Told largely in Iverson's own words, the film charts the career highs and lows of one of the
most distinctive and accomplished figures the sport of basketball has ever seen.
Himself, played by Larry Brown.
Allen Ezail Iverson ( EYE-vər-sən; born June 7, 1975) is an
American former professional basketball player.
Nicknamed "the Answer", he played 14 seasons in the National Basketball
Association (NBA) as both a shooting guard and point guard.
As an NBA rookie with the Philadelphia 76ers in 1997,
Iverson was named NBA Rookie of the Year.
He was an 11-time NBA All-Star, won the All-Star Game MVP Award in 2001 and
2005, and was the NBA's Most Valuable Player (MVP) in 2001.
He was inducted into the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame in 2016.
In October 2021, he was named to the NBA 75th Anniversary Team.
Iverson is regarded as one of the game's greatest scorers, ball handlers,  guards,
and among the most influential athletes in all of American sports.
Iverson attended Bethel High School in Hampton,
Virginia, and was a dual-sport athlete.
He earned the Associated Press High School Player of the Year award in both football and
basketball, and won the Division 5 AAA Virginia state championship in both sports.
After high school, Iverson played college basketball with the Georgetown Hoyas for two years, where he set the school record for
career scoring average (23.0 points per game) and won the Big East Defensive Player of the Year award both years.
Following two successful years at Georgetown University, Iverson declared eligibility for the 1996
NBA draft, and was selected by the Philadelphia 76ers with the first overall pick.
He was named the NBA Rookie of the Year in the 1996–97 season.
A four-time scoring champion, winning the NBA scoring title during the 1998–99, 2000–01, 2001–02, and 2004–05 seasons, Iverson was one of the
most prolific scorers in NBA history, despite his relatively small stature (listed at 6 feet, 0 inches, or 183 centimeters).
His regular season career scoring average of 26.7 points per game ranks seventh all-time, and his playoff
career scoring average of 29.7 points per game trails only Michael Jordan and Luka Dončić.
Iverson was also the NBA Most Valuable Player of the 2000–01 season,
and led his team to the 2001 NBA Finals the same season.
Iverson represented the United States at the 2004
Summer Olympics, winning the bronze medal.
Later in his career, Iverson played for the Denver Nuggets, Detroit Pistons, and the Memphis
Grizzlies, before ending his NBA career with the 76ers during the 2009–10 season.
He was rated the fifth-greatest NBA shooting guard of all time by ESPN in 2008.
He finished his career in Turkey with Beşiktaş in 2011.
He returned as a player-coach for 3's Company in
the inaugural season of the BIG3.